Benjamin Franklin Papers Part 3 -- Letters to Franklin 1778 April-December Mss.B.F85inventory03
American Philosophical Society
- Letters to Benjamin Franklin.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1778 August 19; A.L.S. 4p. (in French); Millin de la Brosse, Claude-Valentin. Paris
    “Recalls that two years before, he obtained from Mr. Deane employment in the American army; unhappy result of that step; was harshly dealt with. Desires now to go to America, as a simple citizen; wishes a small piece of land in Pennsylvania or Maryland, suitable to his rank of lieutenant-colonel, a free passage over for himself and servant and some letters of recommendation.”
  - to The American Commissioners, 1778 August 19; L.S. 3p.; Whipple, Abraham. Brest
    “His delay cause by finding that none of the prizes belonging to the Ranger had been sold and that the unfortunate crew had not received a single sou for all the time they had been in France; allowed then a respite of a day or two to sell their prizes and obtain their money; interference at this point of Captain Jones who threatened he would be the ruin of all those who meddled with the business; indignant at this conduct.”
  - to W.T. Franklin, 1778 may 2; A.L.S. 1p. (in French); Coder, Henry
    Begging him to find the plan of Gibraltar which was submitted to Dr. Franklin by M. [Barbeu] Dubourg, and to give it to his servant; desires news of Mr. [Jonathan] Williams [Jr.]’s health. (In French.)